Our face is hugely important
وجوهنا في غاية الاهمية
because it's the external, visual part
لأنها الجزء الخارجي المرئي
that everybody else sees.
الذي يراه أي شخص آخر.
Let's not forget it's a functional entity.
دعونا لا ننسى انها كيان وظيفي.
We have strong skull bones
لدينا عظام جماجم قوية
that protect the most important organ in our body: the brain.
تحمي أهم عضو في جسدنا : الدماغ.
It's where our senses are located, our special senses --
حيث تكمن حواسنا ، حواسنا المميزة --
our vision, our speech,
رؤيتنا ، حديثنا،
our hearing, our smell, our taste.
سمعنا ، شَمُنّا ، تذوقنا ،
And this bone
وهذا العظم
is peppered, as you can see, with the light shining through the skull
يتخلله، كما ترون، ضوء ساطع من خلال الجمجمة
with cavities, the sinuses,
مع تجاويف والجيوب الأنفية،
which warm and moisten the air we breathe.
التي تدفئ وترطب الهواء الذي نتنفسه.
But also imagine if they were filled with solid bone --
ولكن تخيل أيضا، إذا أنها كانت تملأ بالعظام الصلبة،
our head would be dead weight,
سيكون رأسنا ثقيلا جدا
we wouldn't be able to hold it erect,
ولن يمكننا ابقاءه منتصبا
we wouldn't be able to look at the world around us.
ونحن لن نكون قادرين على النظر إلى العالم من حولنا.
This woman is slowly dying
هذه المرأة تموت ببطء
because the benign tumors in her facial bones
لأن أورام حميدة في عظام وجهها
have completely obliterated her mouth and her nose
قد دمرت بالكامل فمها وأنفها،
so she can't breathe and eat.
لذا لا تستطيع التنفس و الأكل
Attached to the facial bones
تعلق على عظام الوجه
that define our face's structure
التي تحدد تركيب وجوهنا
are the muscles that deliver our facial expression,
العضلات هي التي تقدم لنا التعابير الوجهيه،
our universal language of expression,
لغتنا العالمية للتعبير،
our social-signaling system.
نظام إشارات مجتمعنا
And overlying this is the skin drape,
وهذا المغطى بثنى الجلد،
which is a hugely complex
وهو معقد بشكل كبير
three-dimensional structure --
هيكل ثلاثي الابعاد
taking right-angled bends here and there,
مع الانحناءات الزاوية اليمنى هنا وهناك،
having thin areas like the eyelids,
وجود مناطق رقيقة مثل الجفون،
thick areas like the cheek, different colors.
اماكن سميكة كالخد ، الوانٌ مختلفة
And then we have the sensual factor of the face.
ثم لدينا عامل الحسية للوجه
Where do we like to kiss people?
أين نود أن نقبل الناس ؟
On the lips. Nibble the ears maybe.
في الشفاه وربما حلمة الأذن.
It's the face where we're attracted to with that.
انه الوجه حيث ان ذلك ما يجذبنا
But let's not forget the hair.
لكن دعونا لا ننسى الشعر
You're looking at the image on your left-hand side --
تنظرون في الصورة على يساركم
that's my son with his eyebrows present.
هذا ابني مع حاجبيه يظهران
Look how odd he looks with the eyebrows missing.
انظروا كيف كان يبدو غريبا مع أختفاء الحاجبين.
There's a definite difference.
هناك فرق واضح.
And imagine if he had hair sprouting from the middle of his nose,
وتخيل لو كان شعرا ينبت من منتصف أنفه،
he'd look even odder still.
لكان يبدو أغرب
Dysmorphophobia
Dismorphophobia - الديسموروفوفوبيا (مرض نفسي)
is an extreme version
هو نسخة متطرفة
of the fact that we don't see ourselves
لحقيقة أننا لا نرى أنفسنا
as others see us.
كما يرانا الآخرون
It's a shocking truth
انها الحقيقة المروعة
that we only see mirror images of ourselves,
أن نرى سوى صور مرآة لأنفسنا،
and we only see ourselves
و نرى أنفسنا فقط
in freeze-frame photographic images
في صور مبروزة ثابتة
that capture a mere fraction of the time that we live.
والتي التقطت في جزء بسيط من حياتنا.
Dysmorphophobia
Dismorphophobia - الديسموروفوفوبيا (مرض نفسي)
is a perversion of this
هو تحريف لهذا
where people who may be very good looking
حيث الاشخاص الذين ربما مظهرهم حسن
regard themselves as hideously ugly
يعتبرون أنفسهم قبيحين بشكل مخيف
and are constantly seeking surgery
ويسعون بإستمرار للجراحات
to correct their facial appearance.
لتصحيح شكل وجوههم.
They don't need this. They need psychiatric help.
أنهم لا يحتاجون هذا ، يحتاجون علاجا نفسيا.
Max has kindly donated his photograph to me.
قام ماكس مشكورا بالتبرع بصورته لي.
He doesn't have dysmorphophobia, but I'm using his photograph
ليس لديه ديسموروفوفوبيا ، لكني استخدم صورته فقط
to illustrate the fact that he looks exactly like a dysmorphophobic.
لتوضيح حقيقة انه يبدو تماما مثل مريض الديسموروفوفوبيا.
In other words, he looks entirely normal.
بعبارة أخرى، فإنه يبدو طبيعيا تماما.
Age is another thing
العمر شيئ آخر
when our attitude toward our appearance changes.
عندما يتغير موقفنا تجاه مظهرنا.
So children judge themselves, learn to judge themselves,
لذا الاطفال يقيمون أنفسهم ، يتعلمون أن يقيموا أنفسهم
by the behavior of adults around them.
بتصرفات البالغين حولهم.
Here's a classic example: Rebecca has a benign blood vessel tumor
هذا مثال كلاسيكي : ربيكا لديها ورم أوعية دموية حميد
that's growing out through her skull, has obliterated her nose,
والذي ينمو خارج جمجمتها، أتى على أنفها،
and she's having difficulty seeing.
وهي تواجهه صعوبات في الرؤية.
As you can see, it's blocking her vision.
ويمكنكم الرؤية ، انه يحجب عنها الرؤية.
She's also in danger, when she damages this,
هي في خطر أيضا ، حينما يتدمر هذا،
of bleeding profusely.
من النزيف الغزير.
Our research has shown
أظهرت أبحاثنا
that the parents and close loved ones of these children
أن الأهل والأحباب و وثيقي الصله بهؤلاء الأطفال
adore them.
يغمرونهم بالحب.
They've grown used to their face; they think they're special.
سيكبرون متعودين على وجوههم ، يظنون انهم مميزون.
Actually, sometimes the parents argue
في الواقع، أحيانا يتجادل الآباء
about whether these children should have the lesion removed.
حول ما إذا كان ينبغي أن تصحح عاهات هؤلاء الأطفال
And occasionally they suffer intense grief reactions
وأحيانا أنهم يعانون ردود فعل الحزن الشديد
because the child they've grown to love
لأن الطفل قد نما على الحب
has changed so dramatically and they don't recognize them.
قد تغير بشكل كبير جدا وأنهم لا يستطيعون تمييزهم.
But other adults
ولكن البعض الآخر من البالغين
say incredibly painful things.
يقولون أشياء مؤلمة بشكل لا يصدق.
They say, "How dare you take this child out of the house
يقولون، " كيف تتجرأ على اخذ الطفل خارج المنزل
and terrify other people.
وتخيف الناس
Shouldn't you be doing something about this? Why haven't you had it removed?"
الا يجب عليك فعل شئ بخصوص هذا ؟ الا يجب ان يمحى هذا الشئ؟"
And other children in curiosity come up and poke the lesion,
بعض الاطفال و بدافع الفضول يقدمون على لكز الآفة,
because -- a natural curiosity.
بدافع -- الفضول الطبيعي.
And that obviously alerts the child
وذلك ينبه الطفل بوضوح
to their unusual nature.
الى طبيعته الغير عادية
After surgery, everything normalizes.
بعد الجراحة ، كل شئ اصبح طبيعيا.
The adults behave more naturally,
البالغون تصرفوا بطبيعية اكثر,
and the children play more readily with other children.
وأصبح الاطفال يلعبون بسهولة مع بقية الاطفال.
As teenagers --
كمراهقين --
just think back to your teenage years --
فقط عد بالتفكير لأعوام مراهقتك --
we're going through a dramatic
حيث نمر عبر تغير دراماتكي
and often disproportionate change
وغالبا غير متناسب
in our facial appearance.
في مظهر وجوهنا.
We're trying to struggle to find our identity.
ونناضل من اجل البحث عن هويتنا.
We crave the approval of our peers.
ونحن نتلهف على موافقة من أقراننا.
So our facial appearance is vital to us
لذا مظهر وجوهنا امر حيوي بالنسبة لنا
as we're trying to project ourselves to the world.
ونحن نحاول تقديم انفسنا للعالم.
Just remember that single acne spot
فقط تذكر ان بقعة حب شباب واحدة
that crippled you for several days.
شلتك لعدة ايام.
How long did you spend looking in the mirror every day,
كم من الوقت قضيته وانت تنظر في المرآة كل يوم،
practicing your sardonic look, practicing your serious look,
تتدرب على مظهرك التهكمي ، تتدرب على مظهرك الجاد،
trying to look like Sean Connery, as I did,
تحاول ان تبدو كـ شون كونري ، كما فعلت انا ،
trying to raise one eyebrow?
تحاول رفع حاجب واحد .
It's a crippling time.
انه وقت الشلل.
I've chosen to show this profile view of Sue
لقد اخترت ان اريكم هذه الصورة الجانبية لـ سو ،
because what it shows is her lower jaw jutting forward
لان ما يظهر ان فكها السفلي يبرز للامام
and her lower lip jutting forward.
و شفتها السفلية ايضا.
I'd like you all in the audience now to push your lower jaw forward.
اريد من كل الحضور ان يدفعوا بذقونهم للأمام،
Turn to the person next to you,
و يلتفتون للشخص الذي بجانبهم،
push your lower jaws forward. Turn to the person next to you
إدفع ذقنك للامام و ألتفت للشخص الذي بجانبك
and look at them -- they look miserable.
وأنظر اليه -- انه يدبو بائساً.
That's exactly what people used to say to Sue.
هذا بالضبط ما اعتاد على قوله الناس لـ سو
She wasn't miserable at all.
انها لم تكن بائسة على الاطلاق.
But people used to say to her, "Why are you so miserable?"
ولكن اعتاد الناس على القول لها ، " لماذا انتي بائسة هكذا؟"
People were making misjudgments all the time
كان الناس يسيئون الحكم عليها في كل الوقت
on her mood.
على مزاجها.
Teachers and peers were underestimating her; she was teased at school.
كان الاساتذة والزملاء يستهينون بها ، كانت مثار سخرية المدرسة.
So she chose to have facial surgery.
لذا اختارت إجراء جراحة لوجهها.
After the facial surgery,
بعد الجراحة،
she said, "My face now reflects my personality.
قالت، " وجهي يعكس شخصيتي.
People know now that I'm enthusiastic,
يعرف الناس الآن أني متحمسة،
that I'm a happy person."
أني سعيدة".
And that's the change that can be achieved for teenagers.
و هذا هو التغيير الذي يمكن أن يتحقق للمراهقين.
Is this change, though, a real change,
على الرغم من أن هذا التغيير هو تغيير حقيقي،
or is it a figment of the imagination
أم أنه من نسج خيال
of the patient themselves?
المرضى.
Well we studied teenagers' attitudes
لقد درسنا مواقف المراهقين
to photographs of patients having this corrective facial surgery.
لاستجابتهم لصور المرضى الذين خضعوا لجراحات وجهه تصحيحية.
And what we found was --
وما وجدناه هو --
we jumbled up the photographs
لقد شوشنا الصور
so they couldn't recognize the before and after --
لكي لا يستطيعوا تمييز ما قبل و بعد --
what we found was that the patients were regarded
ما وجدناه هو أنه ينظر إلى المرضى
as being more attractive after the surgery.
على أنهم أكثر جاذبية بعد الجراحة.
Well that's not surprising, but we also asked them to judge them
حسناً هذا ليس مفاجئا ، ولكننا طلبنا منهم الحكم على المرضى
on honesty, intelligence,
على الصدق ، الذكاء،
friendliness, violence.
الود ، العنف.
They were all perceived as being
كان ينظر اليهم جميعا بأنهم
less than normal in all those characteristics --
أقل من المعتاد في جميع هذه الخصائص --
more violent, etc. -- before the surgery.
أكثر عنفاً، الخ. -- قبل الجراحة.
After the surgery,
بعد الجراحة،
they were perceived as being more intelligent,
حكم عليهم بأنهم اصبحوا اكثر ذكاء،
more friendly, more honest, less violent --
أكثر ودية، أكثر صدقا، أقل عنفا --
and yet we hadn't operated on their intellect
ولم نقم بعد بتنشيط احاكمهم
or their character.
على الشخصيات.
When people get older,
عندما يشيخ الناس،
they don't necessarily choose to follow this kind of surgery.
ليس بالضرورة ان يختارو متابعة هذا النوع من العمليات.
Their presence in the consultation suite
حضورهم في جناح الاستشارة
is a result of the slings and arrows of outrageous fortune.
ونتيجة للرافعات والسهام من ثروة الفاحشة.
What happens to them
ما يحدث لهم
is that they may have suffered cancer or trauma.
انهم قد يعانون من سرطان او ورم.
So this is a photograph of Henry,
لذا هذه صورة لـ هنري
two weeks after he had a malignant cancer removed
بعد اسبوعين من إزالة سرطان خبيث
from the left side of his face -- his cheekbone,
من الجزء الأيسر من وجهه -- عظام خده
his upper jaw, his eye-socket.
فكه العلوي ،محجر عينه.
He looks pretty good at this stage.
لقد بدا جيدا جدا في هذه المرحلة.
But over the course of the next 15 years he had 14 more operations,
ولكن في خلال الخمسة عشر عاما القادمة عليه الخضوع لأكثر من أربعة عشر عملية،
as the disease ravaged his face
كلما اجتاح المرض وجهه
and destroyed my reconstruction regularly.
ودمر أعادة التشكيل بشكل منتظم.
I learned a huge amount from Henry.
لقد تعلمت الكثير من هنري.
Henry taught me
هنري علمني
that you can carry on working.
انه يمكنك مواصلة عملك.
He worked as an advocate. He continued to play cricket.
يعمل محامياً ، واصل لعبه للكريكيت.
He enjoyed life to the full,
انه يستمتع بالحياة بكاملها.
and this was probably because he had a successful, fulfilling job
وربما كان هذا لأنه كان ناجحا، وظيفة مرضية
and a caring family
أسرة مهتمة
and was able to participate socially.
وكان قادرا على المشاركة اجتماعيا.
He maintained a calm insouciance.
لقد أكد على الطمائنينة واللامبالاه.
I don't say he overcame this; he didn't overcome it.
أنا لا أقول انه تغلب على هذا، فهو لم يتغلب عليه.
This was something more than that. He ignored it.
لقد كان شيئا أكثر من هذا ، لقد تجاهل ذلك.
He ignored the disfigurement that was happening in his life
لقد تجاهل التشويه الذي يحدث في حياته
and carried on oblivious to it.
وتابع غافلا عنه.
And that's what these people can do.
وهذا ما يمكن أن يفعله هؤلاء الناس.
Henriapi illustrates this phenomenon as well.
هانريابي يوضح هذه الظاهرة ايضا.
This is a man in his 20s
هذا الرجل في العشرينات من عمره
whose first visit out of Nigeria was with this malignant cancer
والذين من أصل أول زيارة لنيجيريا مع هذا السرطان الخبيث
that he came to the United Kingdom to have operated on.
أتى للمملكة المتحدة لإجراء عملية عليه.
It was my longest operation.
لقد كانت اطول عملية.
It took 23 hours. I did it with my neurosurgeon.
أستغرقت 23 ساعة . أجريتها مع جراح أعصاب.
We removed all the bones at the right side of his face --
أزلنا كل العظام من الجانب الأيمن للوجه --
his eye, his nose,
عينيه ، انفه،
the skull bones, the facial skin --
عظام الجمجمة ، جلد الوجه --
and reconstructed him with tissue from the back.
و أعدنا بناءة من نسيج من مؤخرته.
He continued to work as a psychiatric nurse.
تابع عمله كممرض للامراض النفسية.
He got married. He had a son called Jeremiah.
تزوج ، ولديه إبن يدعى جيريمياه.
And again, he said,
وثانية ، لقد قال،
"This painting of me with my son Jeremiah
"رسمتي بواسطة ابني جيريمياه
shows me as the successful man that I feel that I am."
أظهرتني كرجل ناجح كما أرى نفسي."
His facial disfigurement
تشوه وجهه
did not affect him
لم يأثر به
because he had the support of a family;
لأنه لديه عائلة تسانده،
he had a successful, fulfilling job.
وهو ناجح ، لديه عمل مرضي.
So we've seen that we can change people's faces.
لذا رأينا انه يمكننا تغيير وجوه الناس.
But when we change people's faces,
لكن عندما نغير وجوه الناس،
are we changing their identity --
نغير هوياتهم،
for better or for worse?
للأفضل ام للأسوأ ؟
For instance,
على سبيل المثال،
there are two different types of facial surgery.
هناك نوعين من عمليات الوجوه.
We can categorize it like that.
يمكننا تصنيفهم كما يلي.
We can say there are patients who choose to have facial surgery --
يمكننا القول ان المرضى الذين أختارو جراحة الوجه --
like Sue.
كـ سو.
When they have facial surgery,
عندما اجريت لهم الجراحة،
they feel their lives have changed
شعروا بتغيير في حياتهم،
because other people perceive them
لأن بقية الناس أعتبرتهم
as better people.
أشخاصاً أفضل.
They don't feel different.
انهم لا يحسون بالفرق.
They feel that they've actually gained
يشعرون بانهم حقيقة جنوا
what they never had,
ما لم يجنوه من قبل،
that their face now reflects their personality.
وذلك ان وجوههم اصبحت تعكس شخصياتهم.
And actually that's probably the difference between cosmetic surgery
والواقع أن هذا ربما الفرق بين الجراحة التجميلية
and this kind of surgery.
وهذا النوع من الجراحات.
Because you might say, "Well, this type of surgery
لانه ربما تقول ، " حسنا هذا النوع من الجراحة
might be regarded as cosmetic."
يمكن ان يعتبر تجميليا."
If you do cosmetic surgery, patients are often less happy.
إذا اجريت عملية تجميلية ، المرضى غالبا أقل سعادة.
They're trying to achieve difference in their lives.
يحاولون تحقيق تغيير في حياتهم.
Sue wasn't trying to achieve difference in her life.
سو لم تكن تحاول تحقيق تغيير في حياتها،
She was just trying to achieve the face
كانت تحاول تحقيق وجه
that matched her personality.
يتماشى مع شخصيتها.
But then we have other people
ولكن بعد ذلك لدينا أناس آخرين
who don't choose to have facial surgery.
والذين لم يختاروا القيام بعملية لوجوههم.
They're people who have their face shot off.
هناك أناس تم محو وجههم بالنار.
I'll move it off, and we'll have a blank slide for those who are squeamish amongst you.
سأحركه بعيدا ، و ألآن لدينا شريحة فارغة لأولئك الذين على وشك الغثيان بينكم.
They have it forced upon them.
لقد أجبروا على العملية.
And again, as I told you,
و مرة اخرى ، كما قلت لكم،
if they have a caring family
إذا لديهم أسر راعية
and good work life,
و حياة عملية جيدة،
then they can lead normal and fulfilled lives.
يمكنهم ان يكونو طبيعين و لديهم حياة مرضية.
Their identity doesn't change.
هوياتهم لم تتغير.
Is this business
هل هذا عمل
about appearance and preoccupation with it
عن المظهر والانغماس فيه
a Western phenomenon?
ظاهرة غربية؟
Muzetta's family give the lie to this.
أسرة مازيتا أعطتنا الكذبة عن هذا.
This is a little Bangladeshi girl from the east end of London
هذه الفتاة البنغالية الصغيرة من أقصى شرق لندن
who's got a huge malignant tumor on the right side of her face,
والتي لديها ورم خبيث ضخم في الجهه اليمنى من وجهها،
which has already made her blind
والذي تسبب في اصابتها بالعمى مسبقا،
and which is rapidly growing and is going to kill her shortly.
والذي ينمو بسرعة وسيقوم بقتلها قريبا.
After she had surgery to remove the tumor,
بعد خضوعها لجراحة لإزالة الورم،
her parents dressed her in this beautiful green velvet dress,
قام والديها بإلباسها ثوب اخضر مخملي جميل،
a pink ribbon in her hair,
شريط وردي في شعرها،
and they wanted the painting to be shown around the world,
وارادو رسمة لكي تظهر حول العالم،
despite the fact that they were orthodox Muslims
على الرغم من حقيقة انهم كانوا مسلمين متشددين
and the mother wore a full burqa.
و الام كانت ترتدي البرقع كاملا.
So it's not simply a Western phenomenon.
لذا فهي بكل بساطة ليست نظرية غربية.
We make judgments on people's faces
نحكم على الاشخاص من وجوههم
all the time.
في كل الاوقات
It's been going on since we can think of Lombroso
انه موجود منذ كان يمكننا التفكير في لومبروسو
and the way he would define criminal faces.
والطريقة التي كان يعرف بها الوجوه الاجرامية.
He said you could see criminal faces,
لقد قال يمكننا رؤية الوجوه المجرمة،
judging them just on the photographs that were showed.
الحكم عليهم بصور اظهرناها فقط.
Good-looking people
اشخاص وسيمين
are always judged as being more friendly.
يكون الحكم عليهم دائما بانهم ودودين.
We look at O.J. --
ننظر لـ( او.جيه)
he's a good-looking guy.
هو شخص وسيم.
We'd like to spend time with him. He looks friendly.
يسعدنا قضاء الوقت معه ، يبدو ودوداً.
Now we know that he's a convicted wife-batterer,
نعلم الآن انه مدان بالاعتداء على زوجته،
and actually he's not the good guy.
وفي الحقيقة هو ليس شخصا جيدا.
And beauty doesn't equate to goodness,
والجمال لا يعني الخير،
and certainly doesn't equate to contentment.
وبالتأكيد لا يعني أن القناعة.
So we've talked about the static face
إذا لقد تحدثنا عن الوجه الثابت
and judging the static face,
والحكم عليه،
but actually, we're more comfortable
لكن في الحقيقة ، نشعر براحة اكبر
with judging the moving face.
عند الحكم على وجه متحرك.
We think we can judge people on their expressions.
نعتقد أننا نستطيع الحكم على الناس في تعابيرهم.
U.K. jurors in the U.K. justice system
المحلفين في المملكة المتحدة ، في النظام العدلي في المملكة
like to see a live witness
يحبون ان يرو شهادة حيه
to see whether they can pick up the telltale signs of mendacity --
لكي يروا إذا كان بامكانهم تمييز اي علامات للكذب --
the blink, the hesitation.
غمزة ، تردد.
And so they want to see live witnesses.
ولذا يريدون مشاهدة الشاهد امامهم.
Todorov tells us that, in a tenth of a second,
تودوروف يخبرنا بأن، في عُشر ثانية،
we can make a judgment on somebody's face.
يمكننا الحكم على وجه شخص ما.
Are we uncomfortable with this image? Yes, we are.
هل نحن غير مرتاحين لهذه الصورة ؟ نعم نحن كذلك.
Would we be happy if our doctor's face, our lawyer's face,
هل سنكون سعيدين اذا كان وجهه طبيبنا ، محامينا،
our financial adviser's face was covered?
مستشارنا المالي محجوباً؟
We'd be pretty uncomfortable.
سنكون غير مرتاحين على الاطلاق.
But are we good at making the judgments
لكن هل نحن جيدين في اطلاق الاحكام
on facial appearance and movement?
على شكل الوجه وحركاته؟
The truth is that there's a five-minute rule,
الحقيقة ان هناك قاعدة الخمسة دقائق--
not the tenth-of-a-second rule like Todorov, but a five-minute rule.
ليست قاعدة عُشر الثانية لتودوروف ، لكن قاعدة خمس دقائق.
If you spend five minutes with somebody,
إذا قضيت خمس دقائق مع شخص ما،
you start looking beyond their facial appearance,
ستبدأ ترى ما وراء مظهر وجهه،
and the people who you're initially attracted to
و الاشخاص الذين انت منجذب لهم منذ البداية
may seem boring and you lose interest in them,
قد يبدون مملين وتبدأ في خسارة اهتمامك بهم،
and the people who you didn't immediately seek out,
والناس الذين كنت لا تسعى لهم على الفور،
because you didn't find them particularly attractive,
لأنك لم تجدهم جاذبين بصورة خاصة،
become attractive people
يصبحون أناس جذابين
because of their personality.
بسبب شخصياتهم.
So we've talked a lot about facial appearance.
حسنا تحدثنا كثيرا عن مظهر الوجه.
I now want to share
اريد الآن ان اشارككم
a little bit of the surgery that we do --
قليلا من جراحة اجريناها --
where we're at and where we're going.
حيث نقف و حيث نذهب الآن.
This is an image of Ann
هذه صورة لـ آن
who's had her right jaw removed and the base of her skull removed.
والتي تم ازاله فكها و قاعدة جمجمتها.
And you can see in the images afterward,
ويمكنك ان ترى في الصور بعد ذلك،
we've managed to reconstruct her successfully.
لقد تمكنا من إعادة بنائها بنجاح.
But that's not good enough.
ولكن هذا ليس جيدا بما فيه الكفاية.
This is what Ann wants. She wants to be out kayaking,
هذا ما ارادته آن ، أرادت ان تكون بالخارج تجدف،
she wants to be out climbing mountains.
ارادت ان تتسلق الجبال.
And that's what she achieved, and that's what we have to get to.
وهذا ما حققته ، وهذا ما لدينا للوصول اليه.
This is a horrific image,
هذه الصورة مروعة،
so I'm putting my hand up now.
لذا سأرفع يدي الآن.
This is a photograph of Adi,
هذه صورة لـ أدي،
a Nigerian bank manager who had his face shot off
مدير بنك نيجيري والذي أطلق عليه النار في وجهه
in an armed robbery.
في سطو مسلح.
And he lost his lower jaw, his lip, his chin
وفقد فكه الاسفل ، شفتاه، ذقنه
and his upper jaw and teeth.
وفكه الاعلى و أسنانه.
This is the bar that he set for us.
هذا هو الشريط التي وضعه لنا.
"I want to look like this. This is how I looked before."
" اريد ان أبدو هكذا ، هكذا كنت أبدو في السابق."
So with modern technology,
لذا بالتقنية الحديثة،
we used computers to make models.
أستخدمنا كمبيوتر لصنع نموذج.
We made a model of the jaw without bone in it.
صنعنا نموذج للفك من غير عظام فيه.
We then bent a plate up to it.
ثم دعمناه بلوحة.
We put it in place
ووضعناه في مكانه
so we knew it was an accurate position.
وهكذا عرفنا أنه كان موقفا دقيقة.
We then put bone and tissue from the back.
ثم وضعنا العظام ونسيج من المؤخرة.
Here you can see the plate holding it,
هنا يمكنك رؤية اللوحة تثبته،
and you can see the implants being put in --
ويمكنك ان ترى الزرع يتم وضع في --
so that in one operation
وهكذا في عملية واحدة
we achieve this
انجزنا هذا
and this.
وهذا.
So the patient's life is restored.
وهكذا حياة المريض أُستردت.
That's the good news.
هذه اخبار جيدة.
However, his chin skin
ومع ذلك ، جلد ذقنه
doesn't look the same as it did before.
لم يبدو كما كان من قبل.
It's skin from his back.
انها بشرة من المؤخرة.
It's thicker, it's darker, it's coarser, it doesn't have the contours.
فهي اكثر سمكا ، اقتم لونا ، أخشن ملمسا ، وليس لديها ملامح.
And that's where we're failing,
وهنا كان فشلنا.
and that's where we need the face transplant.
ولهذا كنا بحاجة لزرع وجه.
The face transplant has a role
لزراعة الوجه قاعدة
probably in burns patients to replace the skin.
ربما في المرضى الذين يعانون حروقا لاستبدال الجلد.
We can replace the underlying skeletal structure,
يمكننا استبدال البنية الأساسية الهيكل العظمي،
but we're still not good at replacing the facial skin.
لكن لا نزال غير جيدين في استبدال بشرة الوجه.
So it's very valuable
لذا انها قيمة جدا
to have that tool in our armamentarium.
أن نملك هذه الاداة ضمن عدة ممارستنا.
But the patients are going to have to take drugs
ولكن المرضى سيكون عليهم تعاطي العقاقير
that suppress their immune system for the rest of their lives.
هذا سيقمع نظامهم المناعي لبقية حياتهم.
What does that mean?
ماذا يعني ذلك؟
They have an increased risk of infection, an increased risk of malignancy.
لديهم زيادة خطر العدوى ، وزيادة خطر الأمراض الخبيثة.
This is not a life-saving transplant --
هذه ليست زراعة لحفظ الارواح --
like a heart, or liver, or lung transplant --
كالقلب ، او الكبد ، او زراعة الرئة --
it is a quality-of-life transplant,
هذه زراعة لترقية الحياة،
and as a result,
و كنتيجة،
are the patients going to say, if they get a malignant cancer 10 or 15 years on,
سيذهب المرضى للقول ، أن اصابهم سرطان خبيث بعد عشر او خمسة عشر عاما،
"I wish I'd had conventional reconstructive techniques rather than this
"انا اتمنى لو انني املك التقنيات البنائية التقليدية بدلا من هذا،
because I'm now dying of a malignant cancer"? We don't know yet.
لأنني أموت الآن بسرطان خبيث؟" لا نعلم بعد.
We also don't know what they feel
ونحن أيضا لا نعرف كيف يشعرون
about recognition and identity.
حول التعرف و الهوية.
Bernard Devauchelle and Sylvie Testelin, who did the first operation,
برنارد ديفتشيل و سيلايف تستلين الذين اجريا أول عملية
are studying that.
درسوا ذلك.
Donors are going to be short on the ground,
الجهات المانحة ستكون قليلة على أرض الواقع ،
because how many people want to have their loved one's face
لأنه كم من الناس يريدون وجه من يحبون
removed at the point of death?
أن يزال عند موته.
So there are going to be problems
وهكذا هنا ستكون المشاكل
with face transplantation.
في زراعة الوجه.
So the better news is
الاخبار الجيدة هي
the future's almost here --
ان المستقبل هنا تقريبا --
and the future is tissue engineering.
والمستقبل هو هندسة النسيج.
Just imagine,
تخيل فقط،
I can make a biologically-degradable template.
انني استطيع صنع قالب قابل للتحلل بايولوجيا.
I can put it in place where it's meant to be.
استطيع وضعه في المكان الصحيح.
I can sprinkle a few cells,
ويمكنني أن أرش قليل من الخلايا،
stem cells from the patient's own hip,
خلايا جذعية من ورك المريض نفسه،
a little bit of genetically engineered protein,
قليلا من البروتين المعدل وراثيا،
and lo and behold, leave it for four months and the face is grown.
أخفض و أضف ، أتركها لأربعة أشهر و قد نما الوجه.
This is a bit like a Julia Child recipe.
هذا يبدو قليلا كوصفة طفل جوليا.
But we've still got problems.
ولكن لا يزال لدينا مشاكل.
We've got mouth cancer to solve.
لقد وصلنا إلى حل سرطان الفم.
We're still not curing enough patients -- it's the most disfiguring cancer.
لا نزال لا نشفي العدد المطلوب من المرضى -- إنه أكثر السرطانات تشويها.
We're still not reconstructing them well enough.
لا زلنا لا نعيد بناءهم بطريقة مرضية.
In the U.K. we have an epidemic
في المملكة المتحدة لدينا وباء
of facial injuries among young people.
إصابات الوجه بين الشباب.
We still can't get rid of scars.
ونحن لا نزال لا يمكننا التخلص من الندوب.
We need to do research.
نحتاج لعمل بحوث.
And the best news of all
وأفضل الاخبار على الاطلاق
is that surgeons know
أن الجراحين يعلمون
that we need to do research.
اننا نحتاج لعمل البحوث.
And we've set up charities
ولقد أنشأنا الجمعيات الخيرية
that will help us fund
التي ستاسعدنا لتمويل
the clinical research
الابحاث السريرية
to determine the best treatment practice now
لتحديد أفضل الممارسات في العلاج الآن
and better treatment into the future,
ولتحديد الافضل في المستقبل،
so we don't just sit on our laurels and say, "Okay, we're doing okay.
لا نريد الجلوس على امجادنا والقول، " حسنا اننا على ما يرام
Let's leave it as it is."
دعونا نترك الأمر كما هو عليه ".
Thank you very much indeed.
شكرا جزيلا حقا.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)